<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A sad and mournfull lamentation for the people of these nations, but especially for the priests, and leaders of them; and the more because of that which is coming to passe.</title>
            <author>Smith, Humphrey, d. 1663.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 46 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 7 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A60443</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99831497</idno>
  <idno type="VID">35960</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248503708</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing S4071</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R220068</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99831497</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99831497e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A60443)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 35960)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2045:7)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A sad and mournfull lamentation for the people of these nations, but especially for the priests, and leaders of them; and the more because of that which is coming to passe.</title>
                  <author>Smith, Humphrey, d. 1663.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>12 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for M.W.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[[London?] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>in the yeare, 1660]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon; place of publication conjectured by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Tightly bound; print faded.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Quakers --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:35960:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:35960:1"/>
            <head>A Sad and Mournfull LAMENTATION FOR The People of these Nations, but especially for the Priests, and Leaders of them; and the more because of that which is comming to passe.</head>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="to_the_reader">
                        <p>And let all people read it, (and let it have entrance into their hearts) in the feare of God; For it is of much concernment, both for Priests, Rulers, and all people, it being the deep Meditations of my minde, and the true open<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings with the light, and Revelation of God in my heart, sundry times when my spirit hath had secret conference with the Lord, at such times as I have been absent from Men, or in the night season; In a true mournfull state of pitty, towards the soules of all Man-kind, for the eternall good whereof this is written.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <dateline>In Winchester Prison, and House of Correction, being a cloase Prisoner, in a filthy boale, <date>the 16th. day of the 11th. month, <hi>58.</hi>
                              </date>
                           </dateline>
                           <signed>By me that have him to be my life, who is a Man of sorrowes; that of Men am called Humphry Smith.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>MAny dayes and nights, and times, and seasons, for many weekes, and Moneths, of late yeares have many deep, and serious considerations been in me, and many Meditations in my minde, and heart, in the true feare of the living God, and often times in quietnesse (waiting on the Lord God of <hi>Abraham</hi>) hath my spirit had secret, and private, yet plain conference with the Lord, concerning the Teachers, and Leaders of the People, even the hireling Priests of <hi>England,</hi> (and other Nations) and the followers of them. And when I have weighed all in an equall bal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lance, I have found that it hath been in pure love to the soules of all Man-kinde, and without prejudice or envy to them, their Bodyes or Persons, as they are the Creatures of God; And the eternall witnesse of God, in his Covenant of life, hath and doth and will, justifie me herein for ever.</p>
            <p>And when I have looked back upon them Teachers, and see what a stir, and a noyse is made among them, about God and Christ, and faith in his blood, and redemption and justification by him, and all proceeding from that nature in them, which is at enmity with God; And when I have seen how many thousand thousands, and hundreds of times ten thousands following of them, and contending, fighting, stoncing, whipping, and
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:35960:2"/> imprisoning for them, and are guided or rather blinded by them; and when I have seen what care is taken for them, and to uphold them, by the great Rulers of the Nations, even Protector Councill Parliaments, and Justices, (besides many thousands of bruitish people, that are stoning and fighting for them) that they might be upheld, and main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained, yea, even in excesse and fulnesse, from the peoples hard laboures; and when I have seene how many hundred thousand pounds every yeare, they have received from the people; and when I have seene that notwithhanding all this, the people are still in transgression; and so under the wrath of God, and yet know not how to come out of their sin, which seperateth from God, but that many thousands dyed in their sins, and many more are pleading for sin, and many end their dayes in a bed of torment gasp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, strugling, grovelling, and raiging in unquietnesse, under the horrible terrors, of the unutterable fierce indignation, of the wrath of the Almighty, and so goe downe into the pit for ever as many have done, not knowing a resting place, in the peaceable stillnesse of Gods covenant of life, and peace.</p>
            <p>Oh when I say I have beheld, and deepely considered these things, and many more which might be named, and seriously pondered them in my heart, from a true sence of Gods pitty, to the precious souls of all mankind; and from a true understanding of the terrible woes, wrath, horror, and perplexity of spirit, that then comes upon such who thus dye in their sins, not reconciled to God. Even then hath my heart beene broken within me, and mine eyes as fountaines of teares, and a sad lamentation, night and day hath come upon me; and a true mourning for the slaine of the people, who thus are cut off from God; and seperated from the Land of the living. O woe is me be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cause of these things, my soule hath beene oppressed, and my spirit greived; and to the Lord alone hath a greivous cry ascended up, and I have said, oh that I could mourn, and weepe, yet more in secret because of these things.</p>
            <p>And when I have looked upon the Preists, and Leaders of the people; and seene plainely, and truly from the Lord God, that they alone, and that spirit of error, and ignorance in them, hath beene, and is the very cause, of all this disorder, and soule perishing state, that is in and upon the sons of men, and their continuance therein; then hath my spirit said within me, the soule that sinneth it must dye, but the Lord will require their blood at the hands of those that have caused them to erre: and the Lord hath said unto me concerning these Priests and Teachers, my hand is against them.</p>
            <p>And when I have looked farther back, and considered them, who were made Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sters by a knowne law of God that they were declared against by the spirit of Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phesie, and that they were such shephards that could not understand, being greedy, and could never have enough, <hi>Esay.</hi> 56.10, 11. And that they were bruitish Pastors, <hi>Jer.</hi> 10.21. And as Murtherers, and troopes of Robbers; and that the Lord had curs'd their blessings; and made them base, and contemptible in the eyes of all people <hi>Mal.</hi> 2. Then said I, Ah what state then are these men in, who are not made Ministers by a law of God, neither yet sent forth by Christ, <hi>Mat.</hi> 10. But are out of his Doctrine, <hi>Mat.</hi> 13. And so Enemies unto him, being knowne by their fruits, <hi>Mat.</hi> 7.15.16. And are made Ministers by the will of men, and upheld by carnall corrupt lawes, and the imprisoning of hundreds that are come out from them; that we may not partake in the plagues with them, who are seen to be of <hi>Babill, Rev.</hi> 18.4. In whom is found the soules of men, and the blood of all the Saints, from <hi>Abell</hi> unto this day; and they
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:35960:2"/> have been upheld by the devouring of Widdowes houses, the robbing of the Father<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lesse, the spoiling of the goods of hundreds, the imprisoning of many untill death, the rifeling, and robbing of whole houses, as may be witnessed in the county of <hi>Kent</hi> (by a paper titled a horrible thing; and the Record of sufferings for tithe) and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny other parts in the Nation. And when I have beheld these things I have said in my hears, those Ministers, (or rather Deceivers) are far short, and much worse then them in the Prophets dayes, who were made Ministers by a law of God, though they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came as robbers, and murtherers.</p>
            <p>And then have I also lamented the hard hearted blindnesse of many Rulers, in these dayes who have beene worse in their persecuting of those, who from the spirit of God, doe declare against these ministers made by the wills of men, then the Rulers in the dayes of the Prophets, who did not so persecute them, that declare against those who were made Ministers by a Law of God; and surely I have said, did not these Priests bewitch the Rulers, that they cannot obey the truth <hi>Gall.</hi> 3. And so cause them to obey them; or be as it were Slaves or Pack-horses to them; even making their boast in print; that they are still spurring on the Magistrate, as <hi>Richard Baxter</hi> Priest of <hi>Kidderminster</hi> hath written but I say were not the Magistrates blinded by them; and therefore uphold them by their corrupt Lawes, even giving them treble dammages they would soone fall, and come to nought; for they are already fallen under the Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strates, and come creeping to them in the Serpents wisedome, upon their bellyes which is their God, for more dust, or earthly treasure, mony, goods and earthly things; but the Bishops and the Priests in their dayes, were exalted above the Magistrates; and the Priests have yet that spirit of pride, from which they write, as if they rid upon the Magistrates, and spurred them like Horses, and this hath beene so, but it may be other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise, and I have seene how the beast, and the whore, and the false Prophet upholds one another: and ride one upon another, and the Preists spurring up the Magistrates (it's their owne words) and all making war with them that are sanctified, rising up a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst them that are anointed, who need none to teach, and compassing about them whom God hath loved, who are of the Citty where the Lamb is the light, and need not the light of the Son, not the Moon.</p>
            <p>And when I have thus pondered the state and condition, both of Priests, Rulers, and people, and compared them and their state, with the Priests, Rulers, and people in the dayes of the Prophets, and seeing the condition of these to be much worse, and many things more that might be named, and that the latter end of many is like to be mise<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable; And that the name of God is blaspheamed by such, who say they are Christians, and are not, like them, <hi>Rev.</hi> 2.9. And that they are in the blasphemy, though rich Men, who do oppresse the poor in spirit, and cause them to be drawn before the Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment Seats, <hi>James</hi> 2.6, 7. Even then hath the consideration of these things, often times brought a deep mourning upon me; And sorrow hath filled my heart: But when on the other hand, I have seen the work of the Lord secretly going on, in a hidden manner, opening the eyes, and understanding of many Rulers in the Nation; And that many who are, and have been in Authority amongst Men, and in the Army (have already and) are believing in him who said I am the light, and is the Lord of glory, though as a Lamb dumb, and a Man of sorrows, not pleading his own cause, nor having whereon to lay his head, but sick, and in Prison; And that many devout, and honourable Women, as
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:35960:3"/> in <hi>Acts</hi> 17.12. are also, coming, and come to the faith, which purifies the heart, and respects no Mans Person, without which faith in the heart walked by it, impossible to please God.</p>
            <p>And when the eye of my minde, hath been fixed upon that object, then hath my soule magnified the Lord therein, and my spirit hath rejoyced because of him that bring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth, and is bringing salvation, And because of righteousnesse, peace, and true judgment, that the Lord is setting up over all, in the hearts of many Rulers, and devout and ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable among the people, that in righteousnesse through humility they may come to be renouned with honour for ever.</p>
            <p>These things on that hand, (and much which is coming to passe, for an everlasting good among the people, and is revealed in the light, and foreknowledge of God) hath given some ease to my wounded, and troubled spirit, and the refreshings of my Fathers love, hath bound me up in the Covenant of life, with the tender seed, in those whom the Lord is drawing by his love, through humility to the durable honour, and riches which will never fade: Surely herein hath my soul been made as a warred Garden, with the influences of my Fathers love, so that living praises over all hath ascended up to him, whose name is blessed for ever more, because he worketh, and none can let him.</p>
            <p>But when I have looked back again upon the Priest, and the many hundred thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand soules, that are kept in the witchcraft (<hi>Gal.</hi> 3.) rebellion, (<hi>Job.</hi> 24.23.) gainsay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, blindnesse, and ignorance, and the dayly murthering of the soules of so many, then because of the Shepards, who destroy the flock, there hath beene in me a lamentati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and a cry. Oh the Priests, the Priests, surely vengance is prepared of God for them, wrath, indignation, cursing, (<hi>Mal.</hi> 2 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2.14.) bitternesse, torment, perplex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ety, astonement of heart, endlesse misery, and shame amongst men, from the wrath<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full vengance, of the wrathfull terrors of God, will come upon them in a day una<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ware; and their houses shall be left unto them desolate; and they shall become a bye-word among the people, as I have already written, from the dreadfull indignation of the Lord, God of H<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>sts; in a booke titled an Alarum, even so shall it come to passe upon them, behold it is hastning, the Lord God of hosts hath spoken it, and his word shall not faile, neither shall his decree be changed.</p>
            <p>And when these things have come upon me, even as a flood of mighty Waters then have I said in the griefe of my heart, alas for the Priests: the Priests, even the Lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders of the people, where will they hide themselves, in this day of fierce wrath, and fiery indignation, from the jealous God of Majesty, that is neare at hand: Oh how will shame cover their faces, and how will their countenances fall like <hi>Caine,</hi> and how will they curse like <hi>Shimei,</hi> even their God (and their King) who is the God of the World (and their belly is their God) and how will they seek repentance with tears like <hi>Esau,</hi> who might have said he was of <hi>Abraham;</hi> And how will they repent too late like <hi>Judas,</hi> who had obtained part of the Ministery, <hi>Acts</hi> 1.17. And yet denyed him that was the light, and betrayed him who comes to make an end of sin, and was a Devill, and hanged himselfe; and yet had obtained part of the Ministry, alas for the Priests of <hi>England,</hi> are not they worse then <hi>Judas,</hi> did not he bring again, and restore the silver, which he had taken; And can the Priests of <hi>England</hi> do so, nay they have wasted it upon the lust, and pride, even abundance, so that if they themselves, and all that they have left, with their Wives, and children should be sould at the ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>most
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:35960:3"/> value (though I not desire it should be so) yet thereby could they not restore, the tenth part, not one part in a hundred, of the silver which they have taken; nor bring again the mony as <hi>Judas</hi> did, which they have gained.</p>
            <p>Therefore have I said, surely a sad Day will come upon them, when they become a by word, and a hissing to all people, and are turned out of their Parsonages, glebe Lands, Tithes, Treble dammages, and old Masse houses, as their Fathers the Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>shops, and Deanes, and Quiresters, and Singing Men, and Boyes, were turned out of their Pomp, and pride, vain-glory, covetousnesse, exaction, and tiranny, and out of their Bishoppricks, Dena<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ys, and the like; And when also that Gods witnesse shall arise in them, to confound them within, and the light of Christ condemn them for their deceit, and hypocrisie, Tiranny, pride, idlenesse, fullnesse of bread, extortion, and all manner of wickednesse; Oh the Priests, the Priests have said, what a day will this be unto them, surely then as I said, and say again that the Shepheards shall howle, and a bitter Lamentation of the Priests, shall be heard in all the Land, yea the noise of their bitter cry, foundeth already in my heart; and behold I have seen their wee which is near at hand, their Wives also shall be left as Widdowes, and their Children as Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therlesse, and from the pittifull benevolence of the people must they be kept from perishing, in their bodyes; But alas for their soules, who shall deliver them: And herein moreover is their state, and condition the more miserable, because they will not regard this, neither would they at all be warned by them whom the Lord hath sent a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst them, and because they will not see, when the hand of the Lord is lifted up, neither regard the word of his power; Therefore for their envy to the Lords people shall they be ashamed, <hi>Isaiah.</hi> 26.11. that upon them it may be fulfilled which is written, Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold I work a work in your dayes yee dispisers which you shall in no wise believe, though a man declare it unto you, <hi>Acts</hi> 13.41.</p>
            <p>Therefore have I considered, in the very depth of my secret meditations what shall be said or done, in these things, when the Priests have violated the law, and made voyde that which is perfect, and the leaders of the people rebell against the light <hi>Iob.</hi> 24.31. and harden their hearts against reproofe, and will not he warned, that they might escape the dreadfull day at hand; therefore have I said, ah surely the Lord will roote them up, head and tayle, branch and roote in one day: ah fruitlesse trees said I, have not you your selves yet brought forth the first fruits of the spirit which is love, and are not yee your selves yet come to that which fulfills the law of God, to wit love, and are not all without it as sounding brasse, having the Tongues, and the like, make<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a noise among the people, like sounding brasse, and pleasing their fancies as tinkling Cimballs, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 13. and have you been all this while sowing to the flesh: and are you the men who deny him that makes an end of sin, and his blood which cleanseth from all sin, and the faith which purifieth the heart, and are you the men who deny the true light, of him who said I am the light, which lighteth every man that cometh into the world, are you yet the men that deny the Son of God, and will ye not that he should reigne, that is of the seed of <hi>Abraham,</hi> who wandred up and down, and is it you that are saying one to another, and to the Rulers of the Earth, concerning him that is the light, this is the heire come let us kill him, and would you not that he should rule who condemnes sin, and saveth his people from their sins, and maketh an end of sinne.</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:35960:4"/>
            <p>Surely have I said even therefore will the Lord reward you, according to the fruit of your owne wayes; and as you have denyed him, so must you be condemned by him that is the light, <hi>Joh.</hi> 3.19. And as you have been, and yet are (with <hi>Pilat</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers) of <hi>Babill</hi> in the many languages and tongues upon which the whore sits, and as you have been and yet are of the Nations, which are drunke with the wine of the fornication of the Whore, the great Whore mistery <hi>Babylon</hi> that sits upon many waters, and have corrupted the earth, and as you have beene drunk with the blood of the Saints, and made rich by the robbing, and spoyling of the houses and goods of many (even as troopes of robbers <hi>Hosea.</hi> 6.9. Forty in one troope lately at <hi>Dorchester</hi> seed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their belly, their God) and as you have devoured widdowes houses, and been drunk with the wine of the fornication of the whore, and the blood of the Saints: even so shall you have blood to drink, and even so must you drinke the Cup of astonishment, and fierce indignation of the Lord God Almighty, and he will plague you false Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets, with the whore together, and the beast and you must be taken alive, and cast in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the lake of fire, which burneth for ever, and ever.</p>
            <p>And when I have waited to see the end of these things, and pondred this in my heart, in the uprightnesse of innocency and pure simplicity of God; then hath it been said in me, where then will be the memoriall of this Priesthood, of these Nations, who came up since the Apostles dayes, and were discended from the Bishops, that were com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missionated by the Pope and established by the Sea of <hi>Rome;</hi> and what a howling, and a bitter lamentation, will come upon many in that day, when mistery <hi>Babylon</hi> the Mother of all these painted Harlots, comes to be overturned for ever, how then will the great men, and the rich men, and the mighty ones of the earth, mourn and la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, because of the desolation of the Whore: with whom they have all along commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed fornication, and to see these her children (the painted Harlots the Priests of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> who are covered with the Saints words) even dashed to peices with the light, which is the stone that is falling upon them to grinde them to pouder; Alas alas say they how many were made rich; and how many of our Children were like to be made rich by being bred up under the skires of this woman, who hath a golden Cup in her hand, holding it forth to all that will come to her, and how many young men began to love her, <hi>Pro.</hi> 7. Alas say they, were not many of our Children looking at the golden cup, and growing up under her wing, at <hi>Oxford,</hi> and <hi>Cambridge,</hi> and in divers other schools and Nurseries where the Languages and Tongues are, even multitudes upon which the whore sits <hi>Rev.</hi> 18.1. and 15. Who hath the golden Cup at which the Kings, and and the great ones of the earth have drunk abundantly, and must this woman be laid desolate, and must her Children be dashed to peices against the stone (the light) Therefore is the cry great, and the lamentation will be grievous when the iniquity is come to the full, the sin ripe unto judgement, the beast fully fatted for the day of slaughter; and that come to passe which I have seen, which is hastning suddenly, though few can receive these things (unexpected by many) revealed in me, and the more are they, and many other people hardened, and blinded herein, because the Priests are so high, so great, and so strong, and upheld by the strength of such lave, e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven exceeding, and doubling in their power, and authority, the Lawes that were made for the upholding of their predecessors, the Jesuits and Popish Priests, in the dayes of Queen <hi>Mary,</hi> whose Law was but three months imprisonment, and now it is six, and
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:35960:4"/> then the law was but for the Tithes, land now it is three times as much, and so they are more higher exalted then ever, and our task is doubled, and trebled upon us; and besides they cry out we are idle, and wander up and downe.</p>
            <p>But let me reason a little, was it not suddenly after their bondage in <hi>Egypt</hi> was doub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, that the Lord overturned the mighty strength of the oppressors for ever, and was not the cry of the oppressed great because the task was doubled upon them who were in bondage before, and were we not before in bondage under Bishops, and Priests, and Kings, and Tithe, and is it now double, and trebled, and is the little finger of the Priests become heavier th<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n the Bishops loynes, and will not God visit for these things, and doth not this shew that the day of overturning is at hand. But say people how can these things be, they seeming to be established more then ever; yet I reason a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaine with such, who would before hand have beleived, that the Bishops who were for greater then they should have come tumbling downe so soone, with perpetuall shame and reproach; and their Common-Prayer books taken away, with the Priests Idola<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trous surplices, and many such things. And have the Lord began with them the head, and will he not goe on to finish his work, in confounding, and utter overturning the tail and dreggs of them which are yet left behind, and are like unto unnatural children denying their parents the Bishops, and the Pope; and yet creep into their Masse-houses, and live upon the same maintenance, which their parents provided for them, and yet call the Pope Antichrist, (and he is so) their great father who set up the Bishops that established them in their Tithe, personages, and old Masse-houses, and so the Pope being an Antichrist, and they come from the Bishops set up by the Pope, then it follows that they are the dreggs of Antichrist, and if their owne words, writings, way, maintenance and practices be but as it is, and doth appeare, then herein I doe them no wrong, and these things have I also thus considered; and leave to the consideration of such, who are not willing to remaine in blindnesse, that seeing the Bishops are over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned, though they were above the Magistrates, the Priests may also soone be turned downe by the Magistrates, seeing they are fallen under the Magistrates already; and they set them up, and put them in, and turn them out at their pleasure, and may soone turne them downe when they are weary of being spurred by them.</p>
            <p>And as I have considered these things in the meditations of my minde, so have I also considered, the words and wayes of these Priests of <hi>England, Ireland, Scotland,</hi> and other Nations, and what adoe and a stir they have kept, against those Priests that caused Christ to be crucified; And how he suffered by them; and when I have weighed and considered the Actions of them Priests that did so, and the words and actions of these Priests, against them Priests, and the wayes of the one and the other, I have then found, that these in many things are worse then them, though they were very bad; and so both to be denyed, as I have considered according to scripture thus.</p>
            <p>The Priests, the Readers of the Law, which discovers sin but makes nothing perfect, and the Scribes and Pharises had the scriptures, and a large zealous profession thereby, but when Christ the living Minister came, who was the thing or the substance of which the scripture declared from which they had the profession, he being come they knew him not, and therefore for a time the Scribes, Pharises, and Priests, disputed, reason<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and contended with him, and sought to entangle him in his words, and did seek occasion against him, that they might deliver him to the Rulers, and he disputed among
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:35960:5"/> the Doctors, but when much people believed on him, they cryed out, The whole World is gon after him, <hi>Ioh.</hi> 12.19. <hi>Mat.</hi> 22.15. but when he who is the power of God, had raised <hi>Lazarus</hi> from the dead, and out of the grave, then the chiefest of the Priests and Pharises held a counsell against him, then they began to stir, and the beast began to rage, and they said, This man doth many miracles, and if we let him alone all men will believe on him, and the <hi>Romans</hi> will come and take away both our place and Nation, <hi>Ioh.</hi> 11.47.48. And so saith the Priests now, if we let him alone, who is the light, all men will beleive on him, and we shall lose both our place, and Nation, for who will fight for us say they, if all men come to beleive in the light, which lets men see that wars, and fighting comes from the lust, which lust warrs against the soule <hi>James</hi> 4. But one of their owne generation even a chiefe Priest, told the rest they knew nothing at all, <hi>Joh.</hi> 11.49. (The Priests who deny the light know nothing at all) and so these chiefe Priests, and Pharisees, who knew nothing at all sought the life of the Lambe, and to take him, verse 57. And the chiefe Priests also consulted to put <hi>Lazarus</hi> to death also <hi>Joh.</hi> 12.10. And so the Priests now seeke to kill that which Christ the light, the power of God hath raised from death, out of the grave, for now the very thing it self is come to life out of death, and this torments them exceedingly, even more then all the words, formes, disputing, and professions whatsoever that was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it.</p>
            <p>And it was at the Passeover the worship and feast of the Jewes that the Priests sought to kill him that had raised the dead. And when <hi>Jezabel</hi> whose blood the Doggs must lick, at whose table the false Prophets, feede, when she intended to murther the just and take away the life of the innocent, and give his possession to another, she made a feast, and that which feasteth the one thing murthers the other; and at the Jewes feast the one or the other was to be releast; and at the time that they keep the Passeover who are the Jewes outwardly, then he suffers who is the end of the Law, and the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets; and so at the feast of their Passeover the chiefe Priests sought to kill him that is as a Lambe dumbe, and Satan entred in <hi>Judas,</hi> and after that, then <hi>Iudas</hi> went out from Christ the light; and when he went out it was night, and then was the Son of man to be glorified; but <hi>Iudas</hi> who went out from him that is the light, went to the chiefe Priests, and Captaines; and they were glad when <hi>Iudas</hi> was come among them, who was a Devill, and the chiefe Priests made a Covenant with him that was a Devill, and gave him mony to betray him who is the light; And he that took the money, had obtained part of the Ministery, and he was a Devill, and now such Ministers that take both the money, body, and goods, are worse then <hi>Judas,</hi> whom the Priests say was a Bishop, (or a chiefe Priest) because its written his Bishopprick let another take, <hi>Acts</hi> 1.20. And suddainly after the chiefe Priests, had made a Covenant with him that was a Devill, was the Jewes Pass-over, at which time, he that comes to make an end of sin was bet<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ayed, and then Judas (who departed from him that is the light, and was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come a Devill) betrayed the Son of God, and had him led away to <hi>Caiphas</hi> the high Priest, and the chiefe Priests and Elders, and all the Councell sought false witnesse to put him to death, <hi>Mat.</hi> 26.59. and the chiefe Priest rent his Cloathes, and accused him of blasphemy, in whom there is no sin, and they all said he is worthy of death, who said God was his Father; And when the chiefe <hi>Priest</hi> had caused him to be brought before <hi>Pilat,</hi> and vemently accused him of many things, yet <hi>Pilat</hi> would have released
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:35960:5"/> him, and when the chief Priests and Elders saw that, and that one should be released at the feast, and that it might not be the man of sorrows, that is not of the world, but the murtherer and thief, that had stole, therefore the Priests and Rulers then per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swaded the multitude, that they should ask <hi>Barrabas</hi> the thiefe the murtherer, and destroy Jesus the Image of God, that comes to condemne for sin, <hi>Mat.</hi> 27.20. and so to this day at the time of the feast, the thiefe and that which murthers is at liberty, and that is destroyed which comes to save from sin.</p>
            <p>But the Governour said, why what evill hath he done, and <hi>Pilat</hi> washed his hands, and confessed him to be a Just Person, but the chief Priests and Scribes stood and vehe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mently accused him, <hi>Luk</hi> 23.10. but <hi>Pilat</hi> said the third time, why what evill hath he done, I have found no cause of death in him, and yet the Priests even forced <hi>Pilat,</hi> to do that which was unjust, and do not the priests now even force the Magistrates, to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>secute those that they find nothing in worthy of death or of bonds, and so the Priests having provoked, and instigated the people thereunto, they cryed away with him, (that is the light) and crucify him (that makes an end of sin) and the chief priests also gave their voice with them, against him, and so the voices of them, and of the chief priests prevailed to have him slain, murthered, and crucified, who is the power of God that had raised the dead, in whome <hi>Pilate</hi> could find no fault, neither yet <hi>Herod,</hi> and when he was crucifyed who is the light, that condemnes for sin, then the chief priests, and the professors kept their feast, and their passover with the shew-bread, or unleavened bread, which the carnall eye might see, and the murthering priests feed upon, and then they may talk of their ordinances, having slain him that is given for a witnesse, <hi>Esa</hi> 55.4. and so such as slayes the witnesse within are talking of the ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances without, and they cried away with him (that is the bread of life) and they cru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cified him (at whose presence the divells were tormented) and in the time of their feast, and passover (who had the Oracles of God) the witnesse of God lay slain, this may be read within, and upon their sabboth day even the day of their worship (who wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship in the high places) that which came to save from sin lay in the grave, and they were reading that which discovered sin, but make nothing perfect, and him in whome there is no sin, was in the Earth, in the time of their worship, and he that was the light in the Earth was perfect, but that which they read in the high place, made nothing perfect, and the place of holy worship is to be laid desolate, and where Christ (the witnesse) is not risen the sin is not taken away, and there the faith is vain, he that can receive it let him.</p>
            <p>But after the feast, he that is given for a witnesse arose againe, and so before the feast of the Passeover of the Jewes, and Professors, they murthered the witnesse; and for a time while the witnesse lay slaine, they kept the Passeover with outward bread, in an outward Temple, offering the outward sacrifices, but after the feast was over, and their outward worship for a time ended; then he that is given for a witnesse unto the people arose againe, and so that which leades to feasting, murthers the witnesse of God; yet when the feasting is over, and the outward profession and worship ended for a time; then he that is the witnesse ariseth; even the light of Christ in the conscience and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demnes for sin, and then the Priests and Professors were, and are worse then before; and when some of the watch came, and declared that he was risen, who is given for a witnesse (mark they that are upon the watch, are the first that know the rising of the
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:35960:6"/> witnesse) then the chiefe Priests who had mocked him, <hi>Mark.</hi> 15.31. (the chiefe Priests were mockers) assembled with the Elders and took councill againe, for then they were more tormented then before, and that which they feared came upon them, for they said this would be worse then that before, therefore they said of him, this De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver said, after three dayes I will rise againe, therefore said they let a watch be set; least his Disciples steale him away, and say he is risen, and so the last error be worse then the first, and so the Priests called the resurrection of Christ error, and Christ the light a Deceiver, and these Priests now saith the light deceiveth, or is naturall and not sufficient. But Christ the witnesse being risen againe, the chiefe Priests gave large mony to the Souldiers, to tell lyes of him and his Disciples, and caused them to deny the rising of the witnesse, as the Priests doe now, for the witnesse is in man 1 <hi>Joh.</hi> 5.10. And said the Priests if this come to the Governours care, we will perswade him and secure you, <hi>Mark.</hi> 27.62, 63, 64. <hi>Mark.</hi> 28.11, 12, 13. And so the chiefe Priests gave some mony to have him betrayed and crucified; but they gave large mony to have the rising of the witnesse, the Resurrection and the life denyed, after he was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trayed, and crucified, and so them Priests gave their mony to have him betrayed, by him that is a Devill, and gave large mony to the Souldiers, to deny the resurrection of him, and to tell lyes, and the Devill is a lyar from the beginning, and the Father of it. Oh horrible abomination and cruelty that ever the Priests, the Leaders of the people should doe such things as these, and to be found themselves the worst of men, or rather as Beasts: as it is written, I said in my heart concerning the state of the sons of men, that God might manifest them, and that they might see that they themselves are beasts, <hi>Eccle.</hi> 3.18.</p>
            <p>And these things may be a warning both to all Governours, Officers, Souldiers, and People, that they may never more be deceived by, nor joyne to have a hand with, the subtle; treacherous, deceitfull Priests, (against the Innocent) who by their subtilty did and doe overcome both Governouts, Judges, Rulers, Souldiers and People, and so crucifyed the Lord of glory, and maketh it their businesse ever since to keep people from believing in him who said, I am the light, believe in the light, <hi>Ioh.</hi> 8.12. <hi>Ioh.</hi> 12.35.36. and 46.</p>
            <p>But mark and consider, were those Priests wicked herein, and were they murther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers and abominable, then have I considered how much more worse, and how far more abominable are these Priests of <hi>England,</hi> and other Nations thereabouts, who do sel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome give people large mony to tell lies after they have taught them so to do, (unlesse it be, when they hire them to tell lies, and swear too, in bearing false witnesse for them against the Innocent) but they commonly force people to give large mony to them for teaching them to tell lies, and to deny and murther the witnesse in themselves, which witnesse comes to be received by believing in the light, <hi>Ioh.</hi> 12.36. <hi>Ioh.</hi> 1.11, 12. 1 <hi>Ioh.</hi> 5.10. and seeing these Priests do novv get large mony or take it by force, for telling the people many large repetitions in their pulpits, one yeare after another, how Christ was caused to be crucified, and murthered by the other Priests, who gave mony to have it done; and the people knows that already. And when I have con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sidered how many hundred thousand pounds a yeare, these Priests doe receive, and take by force, for telling the people how Christ the light, suffered under the other Priests; and how he that condemnes sin in the flesh, and saves from sin, was called
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:35960:6"/> a deceiver by the other Priests, then have I said surely these Priests are worse then the other, for they gave their mony even large mony but these take mony, and mony that is much more large, and take it by force too, even treble dammage, or three times tre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble what they demand, and rob whole houses, and have got the Rulers to uphold them in it (never such robbers) and take Tithe by force from such as heare them not; and the first Priests that I read of in Scripture who would take the Tithe or offe<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ings by force, were Sons of <hi>Beliall,</hi> and knew not God, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 2.12. and 16. And they said if you will not give it us we will take it by force, and so they that took the Tithe or Off<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rings by force, were Sons of <hi>Beliall,</hi> and such Sons of <hi>Beliall</hi> now, who know not God, doe not onely take the Tithe, and Offerings, but they take even three times, or sixteene times as much in some places, and sometimes the persons of men besides, and those Priests formerly did give their mony, and <hi>Simon Magus</hi> would have given mony for the Holy Ghost, but now these Priests force people to give them mony for their meanings of the letter; and when I have seriously considered these things, I have even stood as a man amazed, saying who would, or how could I formerly have be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leived that those Priests of <hi>England,</hi> were so far worse then them Priests, that made a Covenant with a Devill, and that caused Christ to suffer, or who would have beleived, that they were worse then <hi>Simon Magus</hi> in compelling people to give them much mony for their meanings from the letter, whereas he would have given his mony freely for the spirit; but the spirit they have not to sell, but if they had, what would they not doe for the love of mony, which is so rooted in their hea<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ts, would they not doe as <hi>Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>das</hi> did, who sold him that was his Master, but I do not beleive they would bring again the mony as <hi>Judas</hi> did, though he was a Devill.</p>
            <p>And who could have beleived that these Priests of <hi>England</hi> were so far worse, then the Sons of <hi>Ely,</hi> who were Sons of <hi>Beliall,</hi> and knew not God; for they would take but the Tithe and Offerings by voice, but these Priests take the Tithe, and Offerings, and much more, and the bodyes of men, and women also, and keepe them in prison untill death, for whom they doe no work, and who desires none of their ministry, and if they herein be not worse then the Sons of <hi>Beliall,</hi> let all sober minded judge, and consider this thing w<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>th me, that the first Priests that caused their servants to take the offerings by force know not God, then say I, Alas alas for the Priest of <hi>England,</hi> are they so much <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>then those that knew not God, how doe their shame appeare, and who could have beleived that those Priests were worse then <hi>Iudas,</hi> that was a Devill, who b<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ought the mony againe that he had received, but when doe these Priests, being again the mony and goods, which they have received and tak<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n away by force (though <hi>Iudas</hi> did not take his mony by force) and how hard are these words to be received by such who have not yet come to see and understand these things, and how unwilling will the Priests themselves be, to beleive the truth of this which I have thus weighed, and considered, and pondered in the meditations of my mind, what horrible things from the <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> darknesse are these, that the Priests should be worse then <hi>Iudas,</hi> for after he had betrayed the innocent, he confessed he had sinned, and brought back the mony, but the Priests said what is that to us; and are not these Preists worse then they; for these doe not onely cause the be<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>raying of the innocent, and say what is that to us, but they take mony, and f<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rce people to give them large mony, for betraying that which is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nocent in them, by their subtilty, and craftinesse, whereby they lye in waite to deceive;
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:35960:7"/> and when they have betrayed the innocent principle of God in people, by telling them it will deceive them, yet they will not bring the peoples mony back as <hi>Iudas</hi> did, nor so much as confesse they have sinned therein, but are Impudent. O hard hearted and unreasonable men, have I said what shall be said unto them, surely they are the worst of men, and it had been good for them, they had never been born. Or had a being upon the earth; did the Prophet mourne over or cry aloud unto them, that spent their mony and labour, for that which satisfieth not, oh what shall I then say or write, or how shall <hi>I</hi> cry loud enough or mourn enough yet more in secret, or sound a trumpet, to these dead sleepy Priests, who compell people to give them so much mony, or spoile their goods, and imprison their bodyes till death, for that which is so f<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> from satisfying them, that their soules are murthered thereby, and the innocent <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>thing in them betrayed, and the witnesse denyed: oh who can with hold from declar<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing this, and who can but write it in a booke; that they may see the state which they are in, and that people may know them by their fruits, which did never so planely appeare as now.</p>
            <p>And when these things came upon me, in the deepe meditation of my mind, and conference in my spirit, what a condition was I often in, and how was my soule over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come with sorrow, my spirit with heavinesse, and mine eyes with teares, when did the Prophets eversee, such a generation of Priests as these, and what manner of lamenta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion shall I take up because of these things, surely I will cry aloud unto the Lord in secret, and my soule shall pour forth intercession to my Maker, and with tears as streames of water will I begg at the throne of the most high, for the flame of the people that are killed all the day long, and in this have I beleived that the Lord will heare my cry, and pitty the people that are destroyed for lack of knowledge, that the witnesse of God in them may arise, and that the prisoner of hope may come to deliverance.</p>
            <p>And in this have I not beene hasty as to utter their shame (for I was my selfe a Preacher in the Pulpits) but in a mournfull state oft times many months or yeares, <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> I borne this burthen, neither have I now uttered or written this out of p<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ju<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> to<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>wards the persons of any men; but in the mournfull state, of my long <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, and grieved spirit, from the true sence of the sad, shamefull, and miserable state, th<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> is comming upon them, and the eternall woe, and misery that is like to follow after for evermore. The which I desire they may escape by speedy returning from the way that they are in, now it is so plainly made manifest, to be so exceeding evill.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>H. S.</signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>This being written in true love, and simplicity of heart, for the good of all people, therefore one or two of these may be given, to one or two of them called Church-wardens, or Constables in every Parish in <hi>England.</hi>
               </p>
            </postscript>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed for <hi>M. W.</hi> in the yeare, 1660.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:35960:7"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>